Ford, J. mss. II, ca. 1938-1973 LMC 2495
Lilly Library
Ford, J. mss. II
1938-1973
Lilly Library
Ford, John, 1894-1973.
LMC 2495
1 Box
The Ford, J. mss. II, ca. 1938-1973, consist of award certificates and plaques of film director John Ford, 1906-1976.
Box 1
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Ford was christened Sean Aloysius Feeney but changed his name after joining his older brother Francis, who had taken the name Ford, in Hollywood in 1913. John Ford began his motion picture career as an actor, stunt man, and prop man. In 1917 he became a director on the film The Tornado and directed over 130 films during his lifetime. Ford married Mary McBryde Smith in 1920 and they had two children: Patrick Roper born in 1921 and Barbara Nugent born in 1922.
Scope and Content Note
Several items relate to his World War II service and/or to his contributions to the American Legion.
Related Material
Ford, J. mss. and Ford, J. mss. III, also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 2005
Motion picture film; World War, 1939-1945; Ford, John, 1894-1973.
- Inventory
  - Plaques
    - Harold T. Andrews Post #17 - American Legion - Portland, Maine - Elects John Ford...To Its Advisory Council..., October 20, 1938
    - Member of United Air Lines 100,000 Mile Club..., 1955
    - Director's Achievement Award...International Show-A-Rama 14...Kansas City, 1971
    - College of the Desert Honors You as a Neighbor and Pays Tribute to Your Contribution to the Art of the Motion Picture..., March 1973
    - DesronTwelve [Destroyer Squadron 12]., undated
    - To the Navy's First "Photographic Admiral" Rear Admiral John Ford, USNR, Ret. - From the Members of the Pacific Fleet Combat Camera Group., undated
  - Certificates
    - Translation of Appointment of John and Mary Ford - Maine Department of the American Legion..., June 15, 1950
    - The American Legion...John and Mary Ford...1950 - Regio Mainenis Legionis Americanae
    - OrdreNational de la Légiond'Honneur..., July 11, 1958
    - XVI Festival Internazionale del Film...diploma..., July 28, 1963
    - Department of the Navy...Distinguished Public Service Award..., undated
    - XXXII MostraInternazionaled'ArteCinematografica - Omaggio a John Ford., undated